The Hideout is a horror, mystery, thriller film directed by Pupi Avati.
A mystery-thriller about an Italian woman who moves
to Davenport to open a restaurant.
After her husband commits suicide, she spends fifteen years
recovering at a Minnesota mental hospital.
When she builds herself up enough to begin another restaurant, she
discovers that a murder took place there fifty years earlier.
She decides to investigate and finds a secret plot.
Lei, played by Laura Morante.
Paula Hardyn, played by Rita Tushingham.
Mueller, played by Burt Young.
Padre Amy, played by Treat Williams.
Ella Murray, played by Yvonne Sciò.
Vincent, played by Giovanni Lombardo Radice.
The Hideout (Italian: Il nascondiglio) is a 2007 Italian-American
mystery film written and directed by Pupi Avati.
It marked the comeback of Avati to the thriller genre (a genre he had successfully explored decades before in films such
as The House with Laughing Windows and Zeder) after a series of intimate dramas and nostalgic comedies.
A more silent but very well made film from the Giallo Genre by Pupi Avati, that plays perfectly
with the dark, gloomy atmosphere of an old, spooky house and its deadly secrets.
The protagonist of the film spent 15 years of her life in a mental asylum,
recovering from a nervous breakdown, after her husband committed suicide.
With the intention to start a new life and to open a
restaurant, she moves into an old, historical mansion.
But she starts to feel she is not alone in this big, dark, building..
hearing frightening voices in the darkness and seeing things in the house, she starts to doubt her own mental
sanity again, until she discovers a gruesome crime that happened 50 years back and its horrible secret.
The tone is intense and dark and mind_bending.